<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Learn Finite Elements</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Learn Finite Elements</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an FE code</title>
      <link>/developingfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/developingfe/</guid>
      <description>This page is under development !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kedar A. Malusare</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Professional Experience  Advanced Applications Engineer, 2019-Present Solutions Engineer, Multimechanics, 2019 Project Engineer, Stutzki Engineering, 2014-2019 Research Assistant, University of Wyoming, 2012-2014 Teaching Assistant, University of Wyoming, 2011-2012 Lecturer, Mumbai University, 2011  Education  M.S., University of Wyoming, Mechanical Engineering, 2011-2014 B.E., Mumbai University, Mechanical Engineering, 2006-2010  Interests  Finite Element Analysis Composite Materials Software development  Journal Publications  Malusare, K. A. and R. S. Fertig III. (2014), Composite interaction energy and constituent average stresses for predicting composite failure, AIAA Journal, Vol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Finite Elements</title>
      <link>/practicalfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/practicalfe/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using finite elements</title>
      <link>/ccxtutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ccxtutorials/</guid>
      <description>Spring Elements  Static calculation of a linear spring Static calculation of a nonlinear spring Frequency calculation of a spring-mass system Frequency calculation of a spring - plane strain element combination modal dynamic calculation of a spring-mass system Spring between node and ground (Spring1 element) Spring between two nodes acting in a fixed direction (Spring2 element)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using finite elements</title>
      <link>/usingfea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/usingfea/</guid>
      <description>Basic Mechanics of Materials  Stress Strain Mechanical Properties of Materials Axial Load Torsion Bending Transverse Shear Combined Loading Stress Transformation Strain Transformation Design of Beams and shafts Deflection of Beams and Shafts Buckling of Columns (Problem 1) Energy Methods  Intermediate Mechanics of Materials  Stress and Strain Material Description Basic Structural Members Composite Structural Members Inelastic Structural Behavior Thin Walled Structural Members Energy Methods Elasticity and Mechanics of Materials  Advanced Mechanics of Materials  Stress and Strain One Dimensional Structural Member Influence Functions Stability Plates Introduction to Elasticity Variational and Energy Methods  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>